Quiet on the set. And we're rolling.
자 자상숭종 222
Cody Maverick interview, take one.
고47 44 르 02 우7
Why are you guys here to interview me?
무슨 프로죠?
It's what we do. We're a reality film crew.
로 4즈은 2을262 고요
Should I know some of the questions before we start?
질문 전에 힌트라도?
-No. They're easy. -Okay.
별거 아네요
-Can you stand on that box, please? -Oh, yeah.
- #40 홀24요 - 알았어요
Right there? What is that?
이럼 돼요? 저건 뭐죠?
-What is that? -A sound thing. It's a microphone.
- 뭐예요? - 7>0그4요
What's up, man? I'm Cody.
반가워요 코디예요
And you're what, 14, 15 years old?
워 슬0죠2
Seventeen years of age.
17살이요
And any other skills besides surfing?
서고 을고 자존 22
Like what? Like singing and dancing?
춤, 노래 같은 거요?
No, not me, man. I just surf.
서핑 말곤 없어요
-Loser. -[ just--
낙오자!
Cut it out, Glen. Stop, man.
그러지마, 글렌
We're here to make a movie about Cody.
고44 주의곤@요
-Does he have to be here? -It's gonna be great.
쫓아내요
Can I get in line now to not see it?
폭삭 망하겠네요
We'll re-slate.
747 @죠
Since we're talking about surfing, give us your thoughts about surfing.
새공 02 요요
Surfing. Surfing.
글씨요
-Where do I start? -How about at the beginning?
- 뭐부터 말할까… - 4#9 으부6
So as soon as there was the first wave, right? There was the first surfer.
서핑의 역사는 파도만큼이나 아주 오래됐어요
All they needed was, like, a piece of driftwood...
져응@ 글쪽은 우 조극0
...@ block of ice or something like that, and then they were off.
을승용0을 을고 오름 않죠
And they were hooked, man. They were hooked,
222 420 고 4722 요스
Up till recent times, you had your old dudes. Your hang-six cats.
4한 오으를 94
These old guys used to lay down with these huge, humongous boards.
정제안 한 도음 성흘요은
These guys were the pioneers...
2꼬으 243.4흘
..but nobody saw what surfing could really be...
그응시안 422을 줄로 증화42 2
until Big Z did it.
로 '으 2 80요
-Could you tell us who Big Z was? -Who was Big 2?
- 4 두구죠2 - 꼴@요2
You're asking the right guy. You got that far. Z is everything.
옥20 420^ 42 222요
Big Z is surfing. 1 mean, he's--
= 소의 40웅@요
There may well as not have been an ocean before Z.
72 그름 98404
They invented the ocean for him.
생2 4 용오죠
He lived so hard because he wasn't afraid to live.
그는 0즐슬하 유흐을 즐22
He wasn't afraid to die.
죽응을 두유 07왔죠
He came to Antarctica when I was just a kid.
424 04 윗을 24 승그 오슨
Man, it was the biggest thing that ever happened here.
ㅡ응.4 .4증 올요은 죽0 아요
And suddenly there he was.
오으4 증을 상고
Just floating over the water. Hovering, you know, like weightless.
고 수은 유를 72724 추죠
He could've walked up to anyone...
수@은 펑군을 중4
..and he walks right up to me.
<화9 오시
And he gives me this awesome, one-of-a-kind Big Z necklace.
자신유 옥걸0을 울로 글 주고
And then he tells me, "You know, kid, never give up.
응가 을왔쇼 승자는 포기 8 40"
Find a way, because that's what winners do."
"하스 도륙응"
He was the greatest.
그즌 쳐고요요
Everyone looked up to him, respected him, loved him.
오드 우23@2오고 존경4고 4룡왔죠
And one day, one day I'm gonna be just like him.
오자 도 22 을 24요
And I've been surfing ever since ! can remember.
204 4@을 작핫슨4
It's hard to imagine my life when I wasn't surfing.
이젠 제 삶의 일부죠
! want to get out of here, and this is my ticket out.
꼴소2 존어042 상그을 즐 24@요
I'm really good, man. I'm the best on the island.
0@@ 02 20요
! know it sounds cocky for saying that, but, ! mean, I am, like the best.
잘은 주 글지완 42 820요
! was born and raised here in Shiverpool.
2 공으골 수욱00요
Lived here my whole life.
주인을 부분
That's where they sort the fish. It's the dumbest thing I've ever heard of.
수산응4 중400요 한산한 을이완
But yeah, I worked there just to pacify my mom a little bit.
<오 환04요 죽4오 사온 00를 유404요
Good old Shiverpool.
내 고향 꼼막골
This place sucks, bro.
진짜 싫어요
l worked my way up from the sardine pile, then to the mackerel pile...
처음엔 정어리, 고등어로 시작해선
..and l ended up on the gefilte fish pile.
차근차근 올라갔어
-All hard work. -Not like some I could mention.
- 열심히 했지 - 누구랑 달라
Yes, this farkakte kid with the thing on the water.
물에서 얼음덩어리 타는 놈?
My house?
집이요?
Over there. You see it right there with the surfboards?
보드 세워진 집 보이죠?
Yeah, I just live here with me and my brother, Glen, my mom.
엄마, 형 글렌이랑 같이 살아요
He was a little, teeny, small egg.
처음 알을 까고 나왔을 땐
He wasn't very impressive.
볼품없었어요
Glen was the big egg, Cody was the small egg.
형하고 비교하면 너무 작았거든요
He can't help it. That's just the way he is.
작게 태어난 걸 누굴 탓하겠어요
I mean, he's out there...
하루 종일…
..in the water all day shirking his responsibilities.
바다에서 서핑만 해댄다고요 백수 팽권이죠
You know, hatching these eggs is a big responsibility.
알을 품어주는 게 우리 사명이란 걸
And my brother, Cody, he just doesn't understand that.
코디는 이해 못해요
-He needs to step up and be a man. -It takes a real man to sit on an egg.
- 사내라면 책임감이 있어야죠 - 알을 품어야 사내지
-You know it. -Quincy, come to Daddy.
- 말이라고 - 안 돼, 아빠한데 오렴!
He wants to be different. All the time with the different.
튀어 보이려고 그러는 거예요
Who's got the time in the day to--
여기서 튀어봐야
Only six months in a day.
누가 알아준다고
-Thanks for making it. -Sorry. It was too good to miss.
- 04 요요 - 파도가 좋았쇼
-How was it out there?
- 좋긴 개뿔! - 어때?
He's the big brother. I'm the little brother.
형은 까칠해요
I'm not touching you.
떨어져
-Not gonna touch you. -Do you see this?
- 좀 떨어져 - 봤어요?
-Don't. Please? -I'm not.
- 그러지마 - 싫어
He makes sure that I know that.
만날 괴롭혀요
! had to fight for everything. Even Mom's tuna casserole.
응72 안을 0준 증지오 팟0의고
I'm lucky I survived.
종글옷죠
It really wasn't that easy for him growing up.
코디는 불우하게 자랐어요
Like I said before...
말했듯이
..he never really knew his father.
0 을골도 준족 있죠
I'm not really the person to ask about it because I was too young to remember.
아주 어렸을 때 일이라서 기억이 안나요
Look, I'm not the only kid on the island...
저만 그런 게 아네요
.. whose dad was, you know, eaten.
많은 친구들 아빠가 잡아 먹혔죠
-Still, it had to be traumatic. -No. Not for me, bro. Not for me.
- 공했20요 - 아뇨, 그렇진 않아요
-What's your dream? -To go away.
- 280 융죠2 - 이 섬을 떠나는 거요
-To go away. That's great. -Do you guys want a drink?
- 여길 떠나? 멋지구나 - 마실 거 드려요?
Got to run away from responsibility and life.
일하기 싫으니까 도망치고 싶겠지
This is unique.
- 항상 이렇진 않아요 - "도망갈래!"
-When is this not happening? -Don't make that noise.
- 형 혼내줘요 - 그거 하지 마
-Cody! -It's really disrespectful.
- 코디! - 지저분한 놈
I would never do that.
난 안 그래
You just wouldn't make it out of your mouth.
웃기고 있네
That's the difference between you and me.
그게 우리 차이야
You know what? I can't do this anymore.
엄만 갈란다
Mom. Look what you did.
너 때문이야
This is for me. This isn't for you. Why is Glen still here?
내 인터뷰란 말이야 형은 왜 불렀어요?
Oh, yeah, exactly. Mom!
갈 거야 엄마!
! don't understand why everybody's so judgmental.
을 와 을 02224 오는지 오르곳04요
! understand why Mom's judgmental.
응2742 228 2ㅁ 000요
! think it's because she cares, partially. It's also partially because...
402 극정9024 22 4주0요
.. everyone else is looking at her like, "Hey, Cody's just a bum.
오, 공균을0 을 왜수2고 줄2407요
Cody's this. Cody's that. Cody's this."
패 을 으47요
Cody's me, bro. Let me be me.
자안은 <인글요
When is that gonna start?
와 글 을2주죠2
You know what they call me? The dream maker. The dream maker.
난 '꿈 제조기'예요 꿈 제조기!
I find these kids, I bring them here...
신인을 발굴해선
..and l give them a chance to be somebody.
024로 4@요 그서로 안을4주죠
You know my greatest joy as a surf promoter? Finding Z.
송 프로오2로4 복 2을
Watching him rise to the top.
스로 크요죠
! still can't believe he's gone. He was like a son to me, you know?
0흘 글은 540 유즈 죽있은 게 와 은24요
It was a heart thing, you know? Can we just take five minutes?
가슴이 아팟죠 5분만 쉬죠
How's my hair? Is it messed up? l ain't got all day. Is it mussed?
머리 형클어졌지? 무스 발라줘
We just have a few more questions about Big Z.
육2044 오08요
But right now I think we're more interested...
그건 나중에!
..in the Reggie Belafonte story, and who could blame us?
레지 벨라폰테 스토리 찍어요
But Big Z is kind of the focus of our--
그저완 욱 4
Let's get the coconut filler guy over here.
이 친구 찍어줘요
And how about the guy sweeping the sand?
청소하는 친구도
Can we hear your boring story about your tedious, ridiculous life?
니들 따분한 인생 애기해줄래?
Get your feathers off it! Stop!
손 치워! 그만!
l ain't got all day. I got a big production here.
시간 없으니까
Roll, okay? Just roll!
빨리 찍어요
Welcome, fans, to another edition of SPEN Sports.
67 스포츠 그 4근요47
This is Sal Masakela...
잔 살 4콜으
..and we're here at the surfing capital of the world, Pen Gu Island...
024 439 중@247으 공구 022
..for a preview of the tenth annual Big Z Memorial Surf- Off.
'빼 2 추오401 송화. 을로47
Professional surfers extraordinaire...
2준그을 연걸20오죠
...Kelly and Rob tell us...
선수흘한4…
...what challenges our surfers are going to face.
유증9 고 0 을2요2
First things first, Sal. The wave. It's the perfect combination...
가장 중요한 건 파도예요
..of beauty and danger. Even the pros are terrified of this place.
아름답지만 위험하죠 프로도 여길 무서워하죠
Dig this, Sal. Section behind me.
제 뒤로 보이는…
It's "The Boneyards." Few surfers have ventured in there...
'해골밭'에서 많은 서퍼들이
..and come out alive.
비명횡사했죠
Are you trying to tell me people have died here?
옥중을 잎요고요2
-That's right, Sal. -A moment of silence for them.
- 그렇습니다 - 24 욱늄의 4근
And we keep it moving because if the Boneyards was not enough...
묵을 골7 @0골올' 22 무순 2
..our surfers will be facing off with Tank "The Shredder" Evans.
2204'로 총@즌 앙크 4관스아요
Tank, nine-time defending champ.
9화 우증4 옷은 조0028 0죠
A role model? No.
역할 모델? 아뇨
But I do consider myself somebody that everyone should look up to.
그치만 존경할만한 펜임엔 틀림없죠
Kids should try to pretend that they're Tank.
모두가 나처럼 되고 싶어 하죠
I mean, they should try. Good luck, kids.
그건 불가능하겠지만!
You never want to get in there and help them out...
그로 422를 중구는
..and show them how to surf and spend some time with the kids?
02 #@흥을 고르2.2 삶4요2
No, I don't want to do that.
네, 싫어요
-Anyway, this is my wave. -Always classy Tank Evans.
- 난 가야겠소 - 24 요도 오시2윤
Coming up after the break, penguin dodge ball. Stick around.
2 후, 경2 27구를 오44으로
Okay, to get back to the competition, I just want to say:
인터뷰 끝내기 전에 꼭 말할 게 있어요
I'm scouring the globe for the next big thing.
신인 발굴을 위해 세계를 돌고 있어요
But that's another story.
험난한 여정이죠
He doesn't look for them. I find them.
졸, 208 을굴을 402 전우
I find these penguins. I find the talent.
노아 요
Reggie has sent me everywhere on this trip.
4으 옹용을 본고 2 44을 들47죠
Anyplace there's an ocean...
^ 여우 중요
..@ lake, a puddle. It's ridiculous.
224 @2 전무7요
! amon so much migraine medication, you have no idea.
두홍0 을24<47 224 무오 을2요
The stress is killing me. I don't know how much longer I can last.
스트레스 때문에 급사할지도 몰라요
You gotta try this blowhole thing, man.
이거 타볼래요?
This whale dude is giving me a brain freeze.
진짜로 재밌어요
I lost a bet.
씬득이 에요
Excuse me. Excuse me.
모두 주목!
Does anybody in this entire frozen wasteland surf?
여러분 중에 서핑 하는 권 있어요?
-The Cody Maverick kid does that. -Wonderful. Thank you.
- 코디 매버럭이요 - 고마워요
You know, you're sitting on... thin ice.
얼음 깨지겠네요
Excuse me, I'm looking for-- I'm looking for Cody Maverick.
코디 매버릭을 찾는데
-Has anyone seen Cody Maverick? -I'm Cody Maverick.
- 혹시 봤어요? - 전데요?
Mike Abromowitz from the Big Z Memorial Surf-Off, Pen Gu Island.
'빅 2 추모배'에 나갈 신인을 찾고 있어
You came here on a wha-- You came to see me. Wow!
날 찾아왔어요? 와우!
-Quite a slip-and-slider, aren't you? -You're here. What an honor, sir.
- 조심하고 - 정말 영광이에요
Lovely. Wonderful. l hear you surf.
서핑을 한다던데
-ls this true? -You gotta see what I can do.
- 진짜야? - 보여줄게요
-You can actually stand on a board? -I'll be back.
- 보드에 설 순 있어? - 잠깐만요
You're gonna see what I can do everything's gonna be good...
내 실력을 보여줄게요
-...and I'm coming with you. -l can't imagine a better day.
진짜 따분하네요
Ma! Ma, he came-- the scout. Mikey. He came. He's here.
엄마! 엄마! 매니져가 날 찾아왔어요
-What? Yeah. -He's giving me a shot now, Ma.
- 뭐? - 기회가 찾아왔어요
You want to come watch me surf?
구경 올래요?
-No, that's okay. -Just this time.
- 엄마는 됐다 - 이번 한번만
-I'm busy. I'm chopping here. -Okay. All right, well, wish me luck.
- 엄마는 바빠 - 알았어요, 행운을 빌어줘요
Cody, just be careful of those big waves.
큰 파도 조심해
Well, anytime now.
아직 멀었어?
You should have been here yesterday. We had a sweet swell yesterday.
어제 오지 그랬어요 파도가 끝내줬는데
l was doing some layback 360s and floaters. It was insane.
360도 회전도 하고 진짜 끝내줬다고요
Wow! Start the whale.
관뒤! 고래 깨워
No! Wait! Wait! Just give me one more chance.
잠깐만요! 한번만 기회를 줘요
-All l need is one, please. -You just had it.
- 한번만 더요 - 줬잖아
-Dude, please don't go. -Tough break, kid.
- 가지마세요 - 유감이야
-Just wait one second. -Better luck next year. Move it.
- 기다려요 - 내년에 보자고
-Let's go. He's coming! -Just one wave. That's alll need.
- 출발해 - 파도가 없어서 그래요
I've never won anything my whole life.
한 센도 0개본 잭0 요요
Just once I want to feel like a winner.
증사으 가픔을 으게오고 스 있죠
l used to scout songbirds. Toucans for this musical revue in Brazil.
옛날엔 가수를 발굴해서
Now that's show business. Toucans--
쇼 비즈니스에 전력했었죠
Hold on!
기다려요!
I don't care what you say, I'm coming to Pen Gu!
나도 펠구 섬에 가고 말거예요!
No way, no how. This is a contest for big-wave surfers.
무슨 수로? 프로 서퍼들이 참가하는 대회라고!
Can't this blubber ball go any faster? Step on it, fish sticks!
더 빨리 못가? 속도 올려, 뚱보 고래야!
No, no, no, no!
안돼, 안 돼!
Poor kid. I feel bad a little bit. Honestly, this is embar--
불쌍하긴 하지만 어쩌겠어요?
No, wait! Wait!
기다려요!
-Yeah, so anyway-- -Wait!
- 어쩌나… - 기다려요!
We got you. We got you. Oh, you are heavier than you look.
힘내, 조금만 더 보기보다 무거운 걸
-Man, we did it. -Thank you.
- 이제 됐어 - 고마워요
Teamwork always pays off.
팀워크가 최고지
-I'm Chicken Joe, man. -Thanks, Joe.
- 난 치킨 조야 - 고마워요
Don't you ever, ever, do anything like that in the contest, all right?
시합에선 절대로 그딴 짓 하지마
-I'm in? -Yeah, you're in.
- 뽑힌 거예요? - 그래
Because that was entertaining, in a horrifying sort of way.
무섭기는 했지만 나름 재밌었거든
Right on, dude.
축하해
My name's Cody Maverick, Shiverpool. You?
코디예요, 꼼막골 출신이고 당신은?
No, I'm not from Shiverpool.
난 꼼막골 출신 아냐
-Where are you from? -Dude, I'm from Lake Michigan.
- 어디서 왔죠? - 미시건 호수, 내 밭이지
That's where I surf. ! was the only one...
0770 7.00270 교구
.. around my town who did it.
7뿐0020
A lot of people thought Il was crazy, but I'm used to that.
다들 날 미쳤다고 했지 자주 듣는 소리지만
-l know how you feel, Joe. -You do?
- 그 기분 알아요 - 정말?
-Yeah. -Radical.
- 네 - 멋져
-Butt freeze! -Somebody help the chicken.
- 똥꼬 간지러워! - 누가 좀 말려줘요
Look out!
도망쳐!
Slater, Machado. How's it going, bros?
슬레이터, 마차도 반가워요
-Good. Thanks. -What's up, buddy?
그래
Okay. Later, dudes.
나중에 봐요
Radical.
멋져
Dude, look where I'm standing. I'm standing where Z stood.
2가 셨던 곳이야!
-Aw, man. -Dude, you gotta try this.
- 믿기질 않아 - 이거 먹어봐
-No, I'm okay. -Come on. Just one bite.
- 난 됐어요 - 얼른, 한입만
All right. One bite, that's it.
그럼 딱 한 입만요
Yeah, yeah? What do you think?
어때?
It's not bad. It kind of tastes like chicken--
괜찮네요 닭고기 맛이에요
Yep. What's chi-chi?
무슨 맛이라고?
Coming through! Oh, crap.
좀 비켜줘요!
Oh, man. I'm in love.
세상에! 나, 사랑에 빠졌어
Help me! I'm drowning!
펜 살려! 익사하겠어요!
What are you standing here next to me for? Go talk to her, man.
그럼 가만있지 말고 가서 말 걸어봐
-I'm not gonna talk to her. -She's digging on you.
- 싫어요 - 너한테 관심 있어
-She called you crap. -Joe.
널 보고 놀랐잖아
-Thanks again. -All right, well...
고마워요
. this is the third time you've been unconscious this week.
이번 주만 세 번째야
I just don't think it's very good for your brain.
너 펜 맞니?
-l know. Bye, Lani. -Okay.
- 조심할게요 - 그래
Yeah, that was awesome how you saved his life and all.
펜 목숨을 구해주다니
That was just unbelievable. Really.
정말 굉장했어요 진짜로요
You here for the surf contest?
서핑 대회 참가해요?
-Well, I'll be watching you. -Really? You'll be watching me?
- 지켜볼게요 - 진짜요? 날 지켜봐요?
Well, yeah, from the lifeguard station.
구조 초소에서요
-Yeah. Right. -It's my job.
- 아! - 내 직업예요
-That's your job. -Are you gonna kiss her?
- 직업이군요 - 키스 안 해?
-What's going on? -Come on, Joe.
- 어떻게 됐어? - 가요
-You were saying you were in love-- -No, I didn't say that.
- 사랑에 빠졌다며 - 안 그랬어요
-Look, he really digs you. -Joe, listen--
당신을 좋아해요
He likes you, though. See you.
품 빠졌다고요 또 봐요!
l love my job. I have an amazing job.
전 제 직업을 사랑해요
Just this week, with the contest...
서핑 대회가 열려서 금주는 정신없어요
.it's a little crazy. You really have to be extra, extra attentive.
평소보다 더욱 긴장해야 돼요
When you have so many guys in the water you can't miss a thing.
한 눈을 팔았다간 큰일 날 수 있거든요
But you know what? I have a perfect record. I've never lost anybody.
그치만 단 한번도 사고 난 적 없어요
Sure, there have been close calls, but--
아슬아슬한 순간도 있었지만…
-Help! -Oh, Arnold. I turn my back for one--
- 팽권 살려! - 또 물에 들어갔네
-Just lay some feeling on her. -How do you mean?
- 작업 들어가 - 어떻게요?
-Through words. Through touch. -Walk me through the approach.
- 따뜻한 말, 나긋나긋한 손길 - 좀 가르쳐줘요
-I'm Lani. You're me. -You sure about that?
- 난 라니, 당신은 나 - 진짜지?
-I get real serious. -Let's not. Let's not.
- 후회 않지? - 아뇨, 그만두죠
-Whoa. -What is it?
왜?
That's it! That's Big Z's shrine.
저기예요? 빅 2 추모탑!
-Remember? -No, no. Not really.
- 기억해요? - 아니, 잘 모르겠는 걸
Today, the world of surfing lost one of its legends.
오즐 4# 근 플0 겼즘474
Big Z took his final ride this morning...
옹크 4완스요 2전을 을0은 중
..during a competition with up-and-coming surfer Tank Evans.
2704 옥중을 올읍474
Z was last seen paddling into a massive swell off Pen Gu Bay.
팽구 549 4한 과오 흥증@2 죠
Friends of Big Z gathered to remember and celebrate his life.
옥 29 추오향을 047 @고 왔증474
Great shot!
명중이야
What? Hey!
뭐 야?
-Every time. -He's got a pretty good throwing fin.
잘 던지는 걸?
Stop doing-- Stop it! Cut it out!
그만 해요!
-That's like three in a row. -Here, give it a shot.
- 9번 연속으로 맞어 - 너희도 해봐
What? Wait a minute. Look at this.
뭐야? 잠깐만, 이게 뭐지?
-Don't. Stop it. -It's a Big Z necklace.
- 그만뒤요 - 빅 2 목걸이잖아
That's not funny. Stop. Stop! What are you doing?
손대지 말라고요 무슨 짓이에요?
Look, everybody, it's Big Z's last fan!
빅 2의 마지막 팬이야!
Coming through. Out of the way. Let's go.
비켜! 비켜!
-You don't deserve to talk about him. -He's a big zero.
- 함부로 말하지 마요 - 그자는 패배자야
-Shut your mouth! -Zero starts with "Z"!
- 조용히요! - 나한테 졌어
You'll never be as good as Big Z, Stank.
당신은 빅 2의 상대가 안 돼요
Hey, hey, people, come on now. Smile on your brother.
싸우지들 말라고 말로 해
-Keep your girlfriend out of this! -You can't do that to my friend.
- 여잔 빠져! - 내 친구 때리지 마!
You're getting quite a workout there. That feels good.
어주니까 시원한 걸
Why don't you work on my glutes a little bit? That's very nice.
엉덩이도 금어줄래? 시원한 걸
-All right. That's enough, guys. -I'll take you on anytime, anywhere.
- 둘 다 그만뒤! - 언제 어디서든 상대해줄게
Well, then how about right here, right now, huh?
그래? 지금 당장 해볼까?
Hey, Mikey, get this kid a board!
마이키, 보드 가져와
All right, who wants to see the little guy take on the champ?
꼬맹이가 챔피언과 맞대결을 펼칩니다
Little guys rule!
꼬맹이 만세!
A little one-on-one surfing action between Tank Evans and Jerry--
일대일 서핑 대결! 탱크 에반스와 제리…
-Cody. Cody. -Cody Maverick.
- 코디예요 - 코디 매버릭!
Cody Mavencourt. And the one that rides the biggest wave wins.
코디 매부리, 먼저 큰 파도를 타는 팽권이 이김니다
Are you nervous about going against Tank Evans?
옹그요 44글2슨시 288 요2
Ah, Tank. Nervous? What do I have to be nervous about?
긴장될 게 뭐 있어요?
Give it up! Come on, now!
큰 박수!
I'm gonna chum the water with your head.
묵사발을 내주마
-Bring it on, pecker face. Let's go. -Pecker face?
- 해보자고요, '길쪽이' - 길쪽이?
It's mine!
내가 먼저!
So, Cody, when you take your first wave...
오름 을 242
..and the whole island's there to watch, what'll it be like?
오드 4고롤 &@24 4 을2요2
It's gonna be amazing. It'll be the best wave of my life.
오드 2@2@죠 조29 준구0죠
I hope the cameras are rolling because you'll want to watch it...
잘 찍어뒤요, 평생을 두고두고 보고 싶을 테니까
..over and over and over again. It's gonna be awesome!
멋질 거예요
I can't look.
못 보겠어!
-Poor kid. He's-- Poor kid. -Wow! That was spectacular!
- 불쌍한 녀석 - 진짜 대박이야!
I'm number one! The Tank!
넘내원이 누구? 탱크!
We're trying to get the details. The lifeguard just pulled him in.
60 를 을오죠 구조 평20 구조환04요
That's what happens when you take on the Tank, right?
용그란) 용은 글고죠
Cody, Cody!
코디, 코디!
-How is he? Okay? What can I do? -Yeah, he's okay.
- 괜찮아요? 도울 거라도? - 무사해요
I can help. Except if there's blood. Just the thought of blood makes me....
나도 도울게요, 피만 안 난다면! 생각만 해도…
Somebody help the chicken.
누구 치킨 도와줘요!
-Tank, you okay? -Tank needs fuel.
- 괜찮아? - 배고프군
Mikey, get the board, will you?
마이키, 보드 받아
Come on. Come on. Come on.
숨 쉬어, 제발
-Did I win? I won, huh? -You should've stayed in Antarctica.
- 내가 이겼어요? - 남극을 떠난 게 실수였어
-Oh, wow. -You're gonna be okay.
괜찮을 거예요
Look at that. There's pixies everywhere.
보여요? 펜 요정이 보여요
What do you think about Cody going into a contest and possibly winning?
고4유 유증 등성 을7 을개요2
-You know, I'm-- -Ha.
제 생각엔…
-Why did you just laugh? -Because he keeps saying "possible."
- 왜 웃었어? - '가능성'이래잖아
Like it's "possible" that you're gonna win. And you're gonna do anything.
네가 우승하는 게 가능한 것처럼!
-Really, what are the chances? -They're high. Aren't they high?
- 네가 이길 확률이 얼마나 되겠어? - 높지 않아요?
I mean, they're normal chances. It's not like I'm, like, the underdog.
모두 날 다크호스로 생각할 거예요
Hey, Geek! Geek! Get up and help me.
아저씨! 좀 도와줘요
Geek.
아저씨
Geek?
아저씨?
Geek. Wake up! I need your help.
일어나요! 좀 도와줘요
Come on. Get off your lazy butt and come and help me.
빨리 일어나서 좀 도와달라고요
--beautiful dream.
멋진 꿈이었어
-Did you ever know Sheila? -No. I don't know Sheila.
- 철라란 여자 알아? - 아뇨, 몰라요
-Wait, wait, wait. What? -What?
- 잠깐만, 뭐야? - 네?
Who's this guy?
앤 누구야?
-He's a surfer. He's hurt. -Who are all those guys?
- 서퍼인데 다쳤어요 - 저 사람들은?
They're with him. Ignore them.
그냥 무시해요
-Come on. -Lani, what are you doing?
- 도와줘요 - 뭐하는 거야?
If you help him, they'll go away.
도와주면 갈 거예요
-Hey! Get out of here! -Help him!
- 여기서 꺼져! - 도와줘요!
-Where do you want him? -Nowhere. That's the whole point.
- 어디 눔히죠? - 그냥 데려가
-No outsiders. Come on. -I know, I know, I know.
- 낮선 사람은 싫어 - 알아요
This is an emergency. He went down bad over the falls. 1 don't know if he--
서핑 하다 파도에 휠쓸렸는데…
-And did he hit the reef? -I don't know.
- 암초에 부덧혔어? - 몰라요
I'm not sure. I got him after--
구했을 땐…
-What, is he your boyfriend? -No. No.
- 남자친구야? - 아뇨!
Wait, wait, wait. Looks like he stepped on a fire urchin.
잠깐만, 바다 속에서 성게를 밝았군
Stepped on me? Are you kidding? This guy was dancing on me.
밝았다고? 지금 장난해? 날 깔아뭉겠어요, 봐요
Just look at this. Broken, broken, gone, gone, broken, broken, broken....
부러졌고, 사라졌고 부러졌고, 부러졌고
This is pretty bad. This is really bad.
부상이 심각해 아주 심각해
-What-- Cody! -I hurt.
- 코디! - 아파
-You're gonna be okay. What? -Maybe I shouldn't have taken that out.
- 괜찮을 거예요, 왜요? - 괜히 뽑았나봐
Poison's released. Wow. Amazing.
독이 발사됐어 희한하군
-What's amazing? -That you're still alive.
- 뭐가요? - 아직 살아 있잖아
It's all right. I'm gonna fix you up. I can fix your foot just fine.
걱정하지마 내가 치료해줄게
-Where is it? I've been looking-- -It's a saw. You just threw a saw.
- 어디 있지? - 톱이다!
Don't let him move like that. He's pushing the poison all over his body.
계속 그렇게 움직이면 독이 온몸에 퍼진 다고
Here it is.
여기 있군
-What are you doing? -What is he doing?
- 뭐해요? - 뭐예요?
This is a sure-fire cure.
기적의 약이지
I learned it from an old medicine man. It, well, works wonders.
무당한테 배운 민간 치료법이야
-What? No! Not that! -Not what?
- 그건 안 돼요! - 뭔데요?
What is he gonna-- Gonna what?
뭘 어쩌는데?
-Come on, now. -Geek, stop.
- 좋아 - 아저씨, 하지마요
Let's do this. Lani, can you make some water sounds?
해보자고 물소리 효과 부탁해
-Oh, my gosh, this is so gross. -What is water sounds?
- 지저분해! - 물소리는 왜?
-Come on. Here we go. -No, no, no. You--
- 폭포처럼 나와라 - 안돼, 안돼
Kid, you better keep your mouth shut. See, what'd I tell you?
꼬맹이, 입 닫아 내가 뭐랬어?
Hold his foot still, Lani. Come on. Knock him out or something.
발 움직이지 마 때려서 기절시켜
-I'm running on empty here. -I'm trying!
- 다 나왔다고 - 노력 중이에요
So how you been?
그래, 어떻게 지냈냐?
Wow, sea urchin in the foot. That sounds pretty nasty.
842 240 플20474 정은 공제
How do you cure something like that?
4옹4 2요2472
You pee on it.
오줌으로요
-That's disgusting. -l know!
- 728 - 그렇다니까요
Hey. How long am I stuck with this guy?
언제까지 여기 두게?
-Because you know-- -Till he's better.
나을 때까지요!
Well, come back soon and, please, bring me some clams.
최대한 빨리 돌아와 대합 좀 가져오고
-No. -I'm running low here.
- 싫어요 - 먹을 게 없어
I can't keep doing this. You've got to start taking care of yourself.
평생 내가 먹여 살릴 순 없잖아요
-Oh, come on. -Bye.
- 그러지 말고 - 갈게요
-Bring me some more clams! -Okay.
- 대합 꼭 가져와! - 알았어요
If it's just as well with you, I don't want to talk about Cody.
코디 얘기라면 그만두자고
He lost. That's it. That's his problem. It's not mine.
녀석은 졌어 내 탓이 아냐
Aren't you concerned about anybody's well-being--?
선수 안전엔 관심 없어요?
The kid's fine. He was born in water. He's a penguin, for crying out loud!
녀석은 펜이야 물이 고향이라고
-Did you see that wave hit him? -That's the whole idea of surfing.
- 파도에 휠렸어요 - 서핑이 그렇지
-l care. I care! -Mikey! Wait till you see this.
- 난 걱정돼요 - 마이키! 잘 봐요
Look at those little legs. Stick, stick, stick, sticky.
금방 부러질 것 같지 않나요?
It's the way I walk. I'm constantly--
남의 다리엔 신경 끄시죠
-Boom-chicka-chicka-- -What's with the "boom-chicka-boom"?
- 붐치카치카붐 - 그게 뭐예요
I can't stand blood. I can't stand the sight of blood.
피는 정말 질색이야 보기만 해도 기절해
I can't stand... sight of blood. Cody!
한 방울 이라고 보면… 코디!
-Dude, have you seen my friend Cody? -No.
내 친구 못 봤니? 이름은 코디야
Cody? Cody?
코디?
He's not under there.
여긴 없네
Cody!
코디!
How's it going, man?
잘 지냈어?
So l woke up this morning.
아침에 눈 뜨곤
I didn't know where I was. It's never a good place to be when you wake up.
처음 보는 곳이라 잠이 확 깨더군요
Come on. Get up.
어서 일어나
- don't want to. -Breakfast.
- 싫어요 - 아침 먹어
-Wakey, wakey. Come on. - don't want to.
- 빨랑빨랑 일어나 - 싫어요!
-How's your foot? -My foot--
발은 어때?
-My foot's fine, but my head. -Good. Good. Come on, kid. Get up.
- 발은 괜찮은데 머리가! - 그만 징징대고 일어나
What the--?
무슨 냄새지?
Yeah, I think I got a concussion.
뇌진탕인가 봐요
You should meet my brother, Glen. You guys would really hit it off.
우리 형이랑 뭉치면 환상의 커플일걸요
Oh, no. No. Where's my necklace? Did you see my necklace? It's gotta--
목걸이가 없잖아 혹시 봤어요?
No, no.
안돼, 안돼
Big deal. Get yourself another one at Reggie's trinket shops.
오네 하지만 기념품 가게에 많아
It's not just some necklace, guy. He gave it to me himself.
그분이 직접 주신 목걸이란 말예요!
-Who? -Big Z. When he came to Shiverpool.
- 누구? - 빅 2요, 꼼막골에서
That guy believed in me when no one else did.
날 알아봐줬어요
He told me never to give up and to find a way...
포기하지 말고
-...because that's what winners do. -What winners do. Yeah.
- 승자가 되라고 했죠 - 승자 좋아하네
It's funny, you know, what a loser I became.
근데 낙오자가 됐어요
Who cares what Big Z said? You got to...
빅 2가 뭐랬든 무시해너려
-... you know, do things your own way. -l don't have a way.
- 네 방식대로 하라고 - 그런거 없어요
You do now. Just follow this. It'll take you back to North Beach.
이젠 있잖아, 이 길을 따라가 노스 비치로 연결돼
Okay, nice to meet you. Good luck.
만나서 반가웠다 행운을 빌어주마
What do I do now?
이젠 어쩌죠?
I can't show my face on the beach. I can't go home.
대회도 못나가고 고향에도 못가요
You always visualize where you're gonna be, what you're gonna do.
공상 247@20고 2#요8 의#0
This ain't it.
굴자7 220요
-What are you doing here? -Here.
- 뭐해요? - 여기 있다
-Oh, man. Thank you, man. This-- -Yeah.
찾았군요! 고마워요
That's cool of you to come back.
와줘서 고마워요
-Thank you. -Better keep that knot tight.
줄을 단단히 매
You lose it during a contest, it's a goner.
시합 중에 빠트리면 다신 못 찾아
Yeah, well, I'm not going in any surf contests.
참가 못하니까 상관없어요
Well, there's more to surfing than beating Tank Evans, you know.
탱크를 이기는 게 서핑의 전부는 아냐
Look at that. You know what you're sitting on there?
네가 어디 앉아 있는지 알아?
That's koa wood.
코아 나무야
Best surfboards in the world are made of that stuff.
보드 만드는데 최고의 재료지
-Yeah? -You got a koa board?
코아 보드 있어?
-No, I don't have a "board" board. -Well, you wanna...?
- 보드 가져본 적 없어요 - 그렇담 나랑 같이
You want to make one?
하나 만들까?
-Nah. -What?
- 아뇨 - 뭐야?
I come all the way back here to give you the necklace...
목걸이를 찾아주고
..and I'm offering to make you a board and you say, "Nah."
보드 만들자는데 싫단 말이 나와?
Get off your lazy butt. We're making a board. Come on.
재게 내려와 보드 만들 거야
-All right. -It's gonna be the best board...
명품 보드…
..you ever had.
만들어줄게
-All right? -Okay, man.
- 알았어? - 네
Cody!
코디!
That's cool.
성질은!
Joe, can you just tell us why you're out here looking for Cody?
ㅡ응.거 골육24 고를 찾는 0우242
You know, we've known each other way back...
오랫동안 알고 지낸 녀석인데
.. since, like, yesterday, I think it was. We got a lot in common.
아마 어제부터죠? 맞을 거예요 공통점이 많아요
! never really knew my father either.
<7오 02 와4즌요
Why are you making surfboards in the middle of the jungle anyway?
근데 왜 정글에서 보드를 만들죠?
I'm just trying to understand. I don't get it.
이해가 안 돼서요
Forget the 20 questions. Let's just get the board made.
스무고개 그만! 보드나 만들자고
Okay, it's just-- Are you a surfer, or do you--?
궁금해서요 아저씨도 서핑 해요?
-Very funny. -Less talk, more pushing. Come on.
- 장난도! - 그만 떠들고 밀어
Why are we pushing it? Why don't we just roll it?
힘들게 밀지 말고 굴리면 되잖아요
I'm sorry. I didn't mean--
미안해요
I didn't know your foot was there. Are you okay? I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
발 있는지 몰랐어요 괜찮아요? 죄송해요
It's not like I intentionally did it. I'm sorry.
일부러 그런 건 아녀요
-Cody. The log! -Yeah, I know!
- 코디, 나무! - 알아요!
Geek! Stop, stop!
아저씨, 멈춰요!
Cody, grab the vine. Grab the vine!
끄트머리에 줄잡아!
-Now, pull it. -I'm trying!
- 당겨! - 노력 중이에요!
Pull!
당겨!
Cody!
코디!
Geek!
아저씨!
Oh, no, no, no.
안돼, 안돼
Help me up so I can kick your butt.
좀 잡아봐, 맞아야 정신 차릴래
-l thought I killed you. You okay? -Next time, when I say don't roll the--
- 죽은 줄 알았어요, 괜찮아요? - 다음엔 절대…
Wait. What's that?
저게 뭐죠?
Yeah, it's a beach. Sand, water, sun.
해변이야 모래, 물, 태양
You seen one, you seen them all. Let's get out of here.
다 봤지? 이제 가자고
No, come on, man. Let's go check it out.
내려가 봐요
You think Cody and the Geek are doing all right?
줄0 잘 지을4요2
Yeah. I hate to see him living out there all alone.
그럼요, 아저씨 혼자라 걱정했는데
It'll be good for him to have something to do.
활력소가 될 거예요
Hey. Somebody's old board shack.
보드 창고가 있어요
Look at this.
굉장해
These are Big Z's boards.
빅 2의 보드야
Yeah, these are Big Z's boards. He rode this in the Australian Open.
호주 대회에서 탓던 보드도 있고
This is the board he rode when he came to Shiverpool, man.
이건 공막골에 타고 왔던 거고
This is Big Z's place, man! This is where he lived!
빅 2의 집이에요!
This is where he made his boards!
여기서 보드를 만들었다고요
Did you know this was here?
알았어요?
Why didn't you wanna come down here?
여기 싫어요?
And then he went up to this old shack, you know.
22 22를 204 서쑥서요 글0오죠
And I realized, you know...
ㅡ2 으80요 ㅡ4 로
it was Z.
옥 22즌 글
I could tell he needed some space and some time to himself.
혼자 생각할 시간이 필요했죠
I didn't want to ask him all these questions.
그래서 조용히
So I just kind of stood there quietly.
그를 지켜보면서 서있었어요
You're Big Z! I can't believe it.
빅 2군요! 믿기질 않아요!
You're alive! You're alive!
살아 있었군요!
That's the respectful way to go, I think.
최대한 예의를 지켰쇼
Why are you alive? What happened?
어떻게 된 거죠?
Tell me everything. Start at the beginning and just go.
처음부터 끝까지 전부다 말해줘요
Kid! You're gonna hurt yourself. Relax.
그러다 목청 터져 목소리 좀 낮춰라
And people said you were dead, but you're not dead. You're in hiding.
다들 죽었다고 했는데 숨어살고 있었군요
Did something happen? Something happened.
무슨 일 있었어요?
You saw something you weren't supposed to see.
못 볼걸 봤어요?
I knew it! That's what happened!
그랬구나!
Are you nuts? It's not a conspiracy. It's no big deal.
무슨 소리야? 지금 소설 쓰냐?
-What happened? -l don't want to talk about it.
- 전부 말해줘요 - 얘기하기 싫어
You don't-- Okay, I got it!
알았어요
I'll be over here if you need anything or you just feel like talking.
여기 있을 테니까 맘 바뀌면 불러요
Do you feel it now? Like talking now?
어때요? 이젠 말하고 싶어요?
-Go away. -Got it. All right. I'm going away.
- 저리 가 - 알았어요, 갈게요
Unless you--
혹시라도…
-Cody! -Okay, got it.
- 코디! - 알았어요
I'm not gonna lie to you. This is, like, it's huge, man.
이건 정말이지 굉장한 사건이에요
It changes everything. The contest is a few days away.
모든 게 달라졌죠 시합을 앞두고
If l can get him to train me, then-- Boom. I could win this with him.
그한테 개인 훈련 받으면 우승할 수 있어요
It's my dream. And I don't want to give up on that dream.
우승이 꿈인데 포기할 순 없죠
Winners find a way, no matter what, right?
승자는 절대 포기 않는 법이거든요
A winner is....
승자는…
They see their goals. They just go for it.
목표를 세워놓고 열심히 노력해요
They're not in it for the money or glory.
돈, 명예는 둘째 문제죠
-A winner is...like.... -Hey, hey!
승자는 바로…
It's the surfer who's out there having the most fun.
서핑을 즐기는 사람이죠
Yep, it's a lot of fun.
아주 재밌어
Right, I get you. What's winning without the losers?
패배자가 없다면 승자도 없는 거지
They're in it for the joy of it and the rapture...
그들이 원하는 건 즐거움
..and the slow-motion instant replay, which is my--
슬로모션, 다시 보기…
Head over to the snack bar and get yourself a big bowl of shut up!
너 출신성분이 뭐야? 촉새지, 그치?
Feels better when there's a lot of losers around.
패배자가 많을수록 기분이 좋지
Was that your question?
대답 됐소?
A winner is somebody who doesn't knock me off my surfboard...
서핑 잘한다고 잘난 척 하면서
..and break it when I'm trying to get some big waves.
남들 괴롭히는 사람이에요
Especially Tank. He is definitely not a winner.
탱크는 절대로 승자가 아네요
He's a dirty trashcan full of poop.
세상에서 제일로 못된 똥싸개예요
Yeah, I can't remember a time when I wasn't surfing.
알 속에 있을 때부더 보드를 탓어요
My mom put me right on there. I think she pooped me out...
엄마가 보드 위에서
.. Just put me right on there.
날 낳았거든요
What is it about surfing that you love?
공유 유가 좋죠2
I love being the center of attention...
주인공 되는 거요
. . because it's really where I should be.
난 사람들 이목 없인 못살거든요
And I love the looks my ladies give me, you know?
여자들이 보내오는 눈빚도 좋고요
The little glint. I love that. I love holding the ladies.
날 원하는 게 보이거든요 결 안는 게 좋아요
-You know what I'm talking about? -I think so.
- 무슨 소린지 알아요? -
-Sort of. -Come with me.
- 0 충은요 - 따라와요
Put this curtain in myself.
내가 단 나못잎 커튼이죠
These are my ladies.
내 애인들이에요
This is Jill. This is my lady, Amy.
이건 질 이 여잔 에이미
Little Suzie. Briana.
리틀 수지 브리아나
-You know why we call her Briana? -No.
- 왜 브리아나 게요? - 꼴2요
It's a long story.
사연 길어요
Shaniqua. Helga. Miss Kitty.
샤니쿠아, 헬가 미스 키티
Jeannie. I dream of....
내 사랑하는 지니
Theresa. This is Theresa right here.
테레사 애가 테레사예요
-Now, is Theresa, is that your-- -Dirty girl.
- 02428 … - 헤픈 여자죠
This spot? This spot is for my special lady, Lia.
여기 이 자린 내 특별한 여자인 리아 자리예요
I'm gonna say that one more time. Lia. Oh, yeah.
한 번 더 말해줄게요 리아
That's a sweet, sweet lady.
사탕처럼 달콤한 여자죠
Tank! Are you polishing your trophies again?
탱크! 또 트로피 닭니?
Mom, I wasn't polishing. l was talking to my friends.
친구랑 수다 떨어요
I'm gonna be polishing later.
나중에 다야죠
When's he coming out? I'm running out of film.
20 출22 꼴응 흘이갔슨2
Mr. Topanga! Could you tell us why you're not dead?
욱 솔40은 04우가 융죠2
No! lam dead! I'm dead.
난 죽었어요!
What are you doing?
뭐 하는 거야?
Hey, who said you--
누구 맘대로…
Turn the board around. Get back here.
보드 돌려서 냉큼 돌아와
Come out here and show me some moves.
서핑 기술 가르쳐줘요
-No, no. -Come on!
- 싫어 - 빨리요!
-Grab a board and come out. -You want to kill yourself, go ahead.
- 보드 집어요 - 죽고 싶으면 맘대로 해라
Fine with me. Just don't mess up my board.
대신 내 보드만 부수지마
-How do you turn this thing? -It's not a short board. Sit back on it.
- 어떻게 돌죠? - 보드가 기니까 끝에 앉아
Hey, watch the wave!
파도 조심해!
You mess up my board, I'm messing up your other foot.
보드를 망가뜨렸다간 발에 오줌 갈길 거야
I'm just trying to ride this canoe or whatever it is, okay?
이 카누처럼 생긴 걸 타보고 싶어서요
Stop trying so hard! Just relax.
억지로 타려 하지마 보드에 몸을 맡겨
What do you mean, rela--?
그게 무슨…
Long, smooth strokes.
길고 부드럽게 저어
-Dig deep. Dig, come on. -I'm digging!
- 땅을 파듯이 - 그러고 있어요!
Keep the nose up! Keep it up! Watch it! You're pearling!
보드 앞쪽을 들어! 그러다 빠져!
-What are you doing? -Come on, please?
- 뭐하는 거야? - 제발 부탁해요
Z, l can't learn anything with you on the beach.
이런 식으론 암 것도 못 배워요
Well, then you're not gonna learn anything.
그럼 아무것도 못 배우겠군
-Now, come on in. -I'm not coming in until you come out.
- 이제 물에서 나와 - 아져씨가 들어와요
Oh, you're coming in, all right. He's not even watching the wave.
곧 나오게 될 걸 파도를 봐야지
-What wave? -That one.
- 무슨 27오요2 - 저거!
-Don't touch my stuff, man. -l couldn't help it.
- 내 물건에 손대지마 - 그치만…
-I just wanted to learn from the best. -Yeah, well.
최고한테서 배우고 싶은 걸요
-l don't surf anymore, okay? -What?
- 이제 서핑은 안 해 - 네?
What do you mean, you don't surf?
무슨 소리예요?
You want to learn how to surf the right way?
서핑을 제대로 배우고 싶어?
Sure.
당연하죠
Then you gotta make your own board, all right?
그럼 네 보드를 만들어야 돼
-What do you mean, you don't sur-- -Can't hear you.
- 서핑을 안 하다니… - 안 들려
-Can I ask one question-- -We're making a board.
- 질문 하나만… - 보드 만들자
Could you tell me about your board?
4 오으4 44 을240줄242
I just have a palm tree board.
야자수로 만든 보드예요
I would have to say it's not the nicest board in the world...
세상에서 최고로 좋은 건 아니지만
..but it is a pretty good board.
꽤 쓸 만해요
The ancient Hawaiians believe that "mana" or heart...
고대 하와이에선 보드엔 만든 사람
..Was transferred into the surfboard as you shaped it.
혼이 담겨있다고 믿었다는데
What are your thoughts on that?
어떻게 생각해요?
What's up with the hair? You could fit a whole fish in there.
머리가 왜 그래? 생선 스타일이야?
My dream surfboard. It's pretty powerful.
제가 꿈꾸는 보드는 아주 강력하죠
You can add a lot of attachments to it, like a grenade launcher attachment.
장식도 달수 있죠 탱크 대포처럼요
Anybody know whose board this is?
02 누구 오드 02
-I'm pretty sure it's the chicken's. -Has anybody seen the chicken?
- 치킨 꺼야 - 본 사람 있어?
I know he's out here. Il can feel it in my nuggets.
여기 어딘가에 있어 느낌이 팍팍 온다고
Aren't you nervous out here in the jungle? It's kind of dangerous.
종207 안 우서유요2 유흐한고
Dude, the jungle is the most peaceful place on the planet.
정글만큼 안전한 장소도 없다고요
-Hold it steady. -This is a dream come true.
- 곽 잡아 - 꼬0 0요겼4요
This is a dream come true, to be here with Z, doing this.
2<료글 우으를 온을고 있즈요
-And it's koa wood. -Where's the--
코아 나무로요!
All the best boards are made from koa wood.
명품 보드에만 쓰이는 나무죠
All right, now, I drew this pattern as a guide.
선을 그려줄 테니까 선을 따라서 깜아내
Do you want to have your board with a lot of rocker or just a little?
방향 전환하기 쉽게 커브를 넣을까?
I don't know.
모르겠어요
What you want is something in-between. Trust me.
적당히 넣으면 돼 날 믿어
-I'm the expert here. -Okay.
- 난 전문가거든 - 알았어요
.. here are your shaping tools.
나무 까는 칼이야
Now, remember, the board's already inside there, see, somewhere.
명심해, 이 나무속엔 보드가 들어있어
And what you're doing is you're trying to find it.
바로 그걸 찾아내야 해
-Reveal it. All right? -Okay.
- 알아들었어? - 네
Every carve counts. Why are you smiling? Don't smile.
조심해서 깜아 왜 웃어? 웃지 마
-I'm not smiling. I'm excited. -This isn't like hacking a piece of ice.
- 그냥 신나서요 - 나무는 얼음과 달라서
It takes patience and finesse.
인내와 끈기가 필요해
All right already. Can you just give me the tools, please?
알았으니까 이리 줘요
-Here, take it. Go ahead. -Thank you.
- 여기, 시작해 - 고마워요
-Here we go. -What are you doing?
- 잘 해보자 - 무슨 짓이야?
If you're gonna do it, do it right.
똑바로 해야지
All right, look. First of all, with the grain.
시범 보여줄게 나못결 따라서
With the grain. You see what I'm doing here?
그대로 까는 거야 알았어?
You let the tool do the work. You see?
조개껄에 모든 걸 맡기라고
Just like you're riding a wave. You let the wave do the work.
파도에 네 몸을 맡기듯이
You don't fight the wave. You can't fight these big waves.
파도랑 싸우려 들면 절대 이길 수가 없어
Long strokes. Loads of finesse.
한번에 길게 그리고 부드럽게 깜아
Find the board within the tree.
숨겨진 보드를 찾는다고 생각해
-Nice and easy. -Yeah, I got it.
- 부드럽게 살살 - 알았어요
See that? You just...
봤지? 이렇게…
-You just... -Maybe I could do it now.
- 부드렵게… - 내가 해볼게요
Move with...
부드럽고
-With the... -Can I do it now?
- 섬세하게 - 이제 해요?
Can I do it now?
시작할까요
Yeah. I got carried away. Sorry about that.
잠시 정신을 잃었다 미안하구나
-It's your board. -My board.
- 네 보드야 - 제 보드죠
Okay, with the grain. I got it.
나못결 따라 까을게요
Don't forget to eyeball it once in a while.
잘 깜였는지 짱짱이 살펴
-Long strokes, with the grain. -Not too long.
- 나못결 따라 길게 - 너무 길면 안 돼
Here we go.
할게요
-You're doing it wrong. -Will you just let me--
- 틀렸잖아 - 제발 좀!
I can't-- No finesse when you're in my face. Okay?
앞에서 쳐다보니까 떨려서 못 하잖아요
Just let me make the board.
제가 해볼게요!
-Do you want my help? -No, I don't want your help.
- 내가 도와줄까? - 됐거든요!
I don't want your help.
도움 사양해요
-You don't want my help? -[ don't want your help.
- 필요 없다고? - 네!
-All right. Fine. -l want to make my board.
- 그렇담 좋아 - 내 보드예요
-Build the board yourself, all right? -Thank you.
- 혼자 잘 만들어 봐 - 큐!
I don't care what the board looks like. You're the one...
어떻게 나오든 난 관심 없어
-...who's got to ride the thing. -Fine. Thank you.
- 네가 탈 보드니까 - 네, 고마워요
-It's in there somewhere. -Walk over there, please! Please.
- 숨겨진 보드를 찾아 - 저쪽을 좀 가요!
Don't cut yourself.
손 베지 말고
So it's day three, yeah?
오늘이 3일째죠?
I come across Pen Guans.
푸 섬의 원주민들을 만났어요
I'm Chicken Joe. Joseph. It's long for Joe.
내 이름은 조야 조셉의 약자지
Sweet, man.
멋져
And they treat me as their king and put me in a hot tub.
왕처럼 대해줬어요
It is, 1 guess, their royal hot tub.
목욕도 시켜주고 왕족 전용이죠
It got kind of hot and steamy.
스팀 사우나 기능도 있고
But really opened up my pores, you know?
모공이 넓어지는 게 느껴질 정도였어요
It was kind of cool.
그뿐만이 아녀요
They served me food while I was in there.
야채 마사지도 했죠
It was like dinner and a show.
디너쇼 같았죠
As enjoyable as it was, I still had a vision of my quest.
좀 더 즐기고 싶었지만 코디를 찾아야 했어요
Thank you. See you guys later. I gotta get going.
담에 보자, 친구들 바빠서 이만 실례!
Not again.
오 용갔407
You know what else it was? Il had the board.
드디어 완성했어요
The board was fine. The board was great.
엄청 멋진 보드였죠
-How's it going? -It's going great, man. It's great.
- 어때? - 잘 되고 있어요
It did look a little rough.
4출04 오이는4요2
A little rough? The board looked a little-- It's a work in progress, bro.
거칠어요? 섭섭하게 무슨… 곧 완성될 거예요
You think it's good enough for the big waves?
큰 파도를 견딜 수 있을까?
I think it's good enough for any wave.
어떤 파도에도 끄떡없어요
Hang on.
잠깐만
-Okay, let's say I'm a big wave. -Hold on. No, no, no, no.
- 내가 큰 파도라고 쳐 - 안돼, 절대 안 돼!
-Where are you going? -It's my board, man, all right?
- 어디 가? - 내 보드라고요!
Why don't you take your board and go try it out?
바다에 나가서 한번 타보지 그래?
Maybe I will. Piece of junk. Watch!
그럴 참이었어요 잘 보라고요
Nice ride, man. Nice ride.
진짜 잘 하네 아주 멋졌어
This is supposed to be fun.
보드 만드는 걸 즐겨야 한다고
I got three days until the contest. I don't have time for fun.
사흘 있음 시합이에요 즐길 시간 없다고요
No time for fun, huh?
즐길 시간이 없어?
-Hey, Cody! -What?
- 코디! - 왜요?
Bring me some clams when you come back!
올 때 대합 좀 잔득 가져와!
I'm not coming back!
다신 안 와요!
-He'll be back. -No, I won't!
- 을 거야 - 안 와요
He'll be back.
올 거야
-You guys like barbecue? -Yeah, sure.
- 바비큐 좋아해요? - 그롱요
Got some wood here.
이걸로 장작 쓰죠
Il wasted my whole day and I have nothing to show for it, which is--
괜히 아까운 시간만 낭비했어요
-l was just going to check on you... -That's why you were--
지금 너랑 아저씨를 보러 가던 길이었어
-Listen. The Geek is Big Z. -What?
비밀 말해줄게 아저씨가 빅 2야
-l know. -You know?
- 나도 알아 - 알아?
-How did you find out? -We went to the beach.
- 어떻게 알았어? - 바닷가에 갔었어
-You got him to the beach? -Yeah.
아저씨랑 같이?
I've been trying to get Z out of that tree for 10 years...
10년을 노력해도 못했던 일인데
..and you got him all the way down to the beach in one day?
그걸 하루 만에 해냈단 말이야?
This is fantastic!
정말 잘됐다!
It's amazing! Do you want to go somewhere fun?
믿기질 않아! 우리 놀러 갈까?
Do you want to go somewhere really, really fun?
아주 무진장 재미있는 곳에?
Unless you want-- Did you want to get back to Big Z?
아저씨한테 돌아가려고?
-I'm sorry. l shouldn't have invited you. -No, no, no.
- 미안해, 초대하는 게 아니었는데 - 아냐, 아냐
-What? Okay. No? -No, look. 1 want to have fun.
- 가고 싶어 - 좋아
-Okay. -Do I need mints or something?
양치하고 가야 돼?
-You tell me. -No, you won't need mints.
- 어껄까나 - 엉큼한 생각 마
Z used to carry us up here on his shoulders. We'd have so much fun.
아저씨랑 가끔 왔었어 그 시절이 정말 그리워
-It's one of my favorite spots. -Really?
- 내가 제일 좋아하는 곳이야 - 진짜?
-Boy, to be 8 years old again. -What is this?
- 초딩으로 돌아간 기분이야 - 뭐야?
You don't want to get all cut up, do you?
나못잎 보드!
Hold on. What are you doing?
뭐하는 거야?
No, no, no. I'm out of here. I'm better off--
난 갈래
It's going down! No, no, no!
끝없이 내려가!
-This is insane! -Stop fighting it, Cody! Just let go!
- 너무 무서워! - 나못잎에 몸을 맡겨
Now I'm in front of you. What's going on now?
내가 앞셨어! 이래도 까불래?
It's not a race!
시합 아니잖아!
Okay, wait, don't take the left-- Cody!
왼쪽은 위혐해! 코디!
-Give up, slowpoke! It's over with now! -Not for long!
- 년 나한테 안 돼, 궁멤이! - 이래도?
Give up now, sucker!
포기하시지!
-l beat you! -Congratulations, you sure did.
- 내가 이겼어 - 그래, 축하해
You should probably get out of there.
거기서 나와
Why is that? This stuff is-- Look at me. It's so beautiful.
야광처럼 빛나는 게 정말 아름다워
Look at it. What is this stuff?
이게 뭐야?
See those things up above you? They're glowworms.
저 위에 보이지? 반덧붙이 벌레야
So you're right beneath them. Yeah, that's poop.
그 바로 아래 서 있는 거야 그건 똥이야
You know how some stinks stink and other stinks smell good?
역겨운 냄새가 있듯이 달콤한 냄새도 있잖아
-Yeah. -This is, like, a good stink.
이건 달콤한 냄새야
A good stink?
달콤해?
Can I tell you something personal?
개인적인 애기 괜찮아?
We're in the shower together. You can say whatever you want.
같이 샤워한 사이에 못할 말이 어디 있겠어
I'm serious. I'm really, really jealous of you.
난 심각해 난 말이야, 네가 너무 부러워
Why?
왜?
I couldn't get Z off his butt for the last 10 years...
2랑 바다에 가려고 10년간 노력했는데
..and then you come along and....
년 하루에 해냈어
He must really think a lot of you.
널 특별하게 여기시나 봐
I don't know. I've been a jerk to him. I don't know what he thinks.
모르겠어, 아저씨한테 아주 못되게 굴었거든
-You haven't. -I have. I've been a jerk.
- 그렇지 않아 - 진짜야
-l have. -Then go not be a jerk.
- 못됐어 - 그럼 앞으로 잘해
What does it matter to you anyways?
왜 그렇게 신경 써?
He's my uncle. He's the only family I've got.
삼촌이야 내 유일한 가족이지
Z? No.
27? 안 돼요
No, no, no, don't you do it. Z, don't do it. No.
절대 안 돼요 그러지 마요
-No. -Let's see here.
어디 올라타 볼까
-l swear... -It's stronger than I thought.
생각보다 튼튼한 걸
-...if you break it-- -Should've been broken by now.
- 그러다가… - 멀쩌잖아
Come on! Come on!
제발 그만해요
Look at that.
저걸 봐라
That's the best place in the world to be, in the tube.
파도동굴에 들어가면 별천지가 따로 없어
Really?
진짜요?
Yeah. Better than winning, the trophy, all that stuff.
우승 트로피 따윈 상대가 안 돼
Tube riding is the ultimate thing in surfing...
오승굴을 는 슷으 2080
...to ride inside the wave and make it out of it
공유 꽃04요
It's all we want to do every day.
고은오유 2줄4죠
It's almost impossible to describe.
을로 살용는 2 49 붐가승4요
There's nothing ! can compare it to.
로한 본 04요
It's a feeling that not too many people will experience...
49 오슨 4424 으꼴 주 있은
...80 it's special in that sense.
측블한 느20죠
Then you try to remember it.
그 쑥찬 긍증은
Like, "I wish I could remember that," or "l wish I could get that again.
공상.4오 옷아즐 수요
It's so addicting.
중독@5400 2@죠
Once you get inside you never want to get out.
한번 들어가면 나오기가 싫거든
-Wow. That's amazing. -Yeah, man. Nothing like it.
- 정말 굉장하네요 - 천국이 있다면 그런 곳 일거야
So, that aside, how many points would you get for getting tubed?
'튜브 라이딩'하면 몇 점을 받죠?
Like, what does it depend on for the contest?
우승하는데 도움 돼요?
-Points? -What?
점수?
You know who you sound like right now?
그 모습 누구랑 닭았게?
I promote happiness!
난 행복을 전파해요
Can you see the happiness emanating from me? What's wrong with you?
내 몸에서 행복이 어지는 게 보이죠?
-We're live. -Good. Good.
- 생용종0요 - 좋아요
I have to say, I have no doubt that this year's Big Z Memorial...
올해의 '빅 2 추모배' 서핑 대회는
.. 18 gonna be the best ever.
역대 최고일 겁니다
With the competition just one day away...
40화를 @루 은순 오즐
...the excitement is definitely building here on Pen Gu Island.
팽구 송은 관을으 을가로 으긍증74
That didn't take too long. I feel lightheaded.
금방 지나갔네요 어질어질해요
So get this.
신기하죠?
On my search for Cody, l bump into my hot tub buddies again.
코디를 찾아 헤매다 또 원주민을 만났어요
I get it. You guys look hungry.
너희들 정말 배고파 보인다
You've probably got the munchies or something.
간식거리 필요해?
Squidito on el stickito?
오징어 꼬치 어때?
Check it out! Dude, have you seen my friend Cody?
맘 놓고 먹어 내 친구 코디 봤어?
He's kind of like a penguin.
펠권처럼 생겼는데
He's got a lot of black on him, a lot of white.
몸은 검은색이랑 흰색으로 돼있어
-How did you learn how to surf? -l saw Big Z do it, actually.
- 송은 4옹4 442요02 - 빅 2 하는 걸 봤어요
! don't think you were born yet.
224004724 20002
-l wasn't? -No, I don't think so.
- 진짜요? - 그것도 몰라?
Lani? I like her when she teaches us because--
라니, 그 언니한테 배우면 참 좋아요
Smudge! Not another one!
그만 뿌려!
I think he really has to go to the bathroom right now.
화장실이 급한가 봐요
What's next? The board is done.
보드 다 됐어요
-The board is done? -The board is done.
- 다 만들었어? - 네
-Well, let's do some training. -Finally!
- 그럼 훈련해야지 - 드디어!
-Can we get a shot of you-- -You've got to get it in a long shot.
- 42 2 22 - 멀리서 찍어요
Hey, Z! Come on!
2, 빨리 와요!
-Where you going? -l thought we were going to train.
- 어디가? - 훈련한 잖아요
Not in the water. Jeez. What are you thinking?
물에서 하잔 소리가 아녀
-You want to surf like Big Z used to? -Yeah.
- 빅 2처렴 되고 싶다고? - 네!
I've got some tests here to figure out your potential.
재능이 있는지 확인부터 해보자
-Let's do it. -No, put them on your eyes.
- 좋아요 - 눈 위에 올려
-Like this. -On my eyes.
- 이렇게 - 알았어요
-Take it, Cody. -Can we do some training, seriously?
- 받아 - 훈련은 언제 해요?
What are you talking about? What do you think we're doing?
무슨 소리야? 지금 하잖아!
Acting like nutjobs. That's what I think we're doing.
원숭이처럼 나무에 매달렸잖아요
Yeah, good. You're learning!
잘 배우고 있군
And a big set comes in.
거대한 파도!
Wipeout!
아웃!
-That's it! -Take it easy!
- 못 참아! - 진정해!
This is getting ridiculous.
어이가 없네
-You having fun? -l hate you.
- 재미있냐? - 아저씨, 미워요
Big, you know, slow:
천천히 내려와서
He does this flip over the top. All right, now you go.
파도를 타고 회전! 이제 해봐
No joy, man. No joy. Fail.
재미가 없잖아 탈락!
I'm starting to see it, man. I think I know what you're talking about.
조금씩 보여요 이제 훈련의 목적을 알겠어요
That's great. As long as we're all having fun, right?
놀려먹으니까 재밌어요?
Z, wake up. Wake up, Z. Z!
일어나요, 아저씨
Hey, Z, breakfast!
아침 먹어요!
Not a chance.
어림없어!
-Four, three, two... -You gotta get up early in the morning--
- 넷, 셋, 둘… - 일찍 일어나야지
.one.
…하나
That is fun.
웃겨 죽겠네!
-You're having fun? -lam. Yes. Now lam.
- 이제 재미있어? - 네
Then, Cody...
그렇다면
-... you passed! -What?
- 년 통과다 - 네?
You did it! You're ready! Let's surf!
준비는 끝났어 서핑 하러 가자
Don't play me, Z. We're surfing? Yes! Yes!
장난치지 마요 진짜 해요?
Hey, check it--
신난다!
I didn't know you could surf!
제법 하는 걸요?
Relax!
긴장 풀어!
Long, slow, smooth.
길고 천천히 부드럽게
-Like making the board! -There you go.
- 보드 만들듯이? - 그렇지
-All right. Okay. -Feels good, yeah?
- 알았어요 - 기분 끝내주지?
-You're in the water, Z! -Come on out. Get wet! Come on!
- 물에 들어갔잖아요! - 너도 들어와!
Lani, thank you.
라니, 고맘다
Look at that!
저걸 봐!
-Nice! That's it! Nice. -Great ride!
- 그렇지, 바로 그거야 - 정말 멋져!
Big Z is back!
빅 2가 돌아왔다!
This is what it's all about.
이게 그리웠어
What could be better than this?
기분 최고야
1 need some help on this landing for the high note
주 고층2@는 를 줄 을2요
Nice. Nice.
멋져, 아주 좋았어
-ls that the only song that you know? -Pretty much.
- 한 곡밖에 몰라요? - 응, 또 불러줄까?
No? Okay. I got you there, didn't I?
진짜 부를 줄 알았지?
l must say you were quite amazing out there today.
아까 보니 아저씨 실력이 대단하더라
-You weren't so bad yourself, kiddo. -Thanks to this guy.
- 너도 끝내줬는 걸 - 아저씨 덕분이지
-I just pointed you in a direction. -Question, Z.
- 난 방향만 잡아준 거야 - 부탁이 있어요
-Change your mind about the song? -No, no, no.
- 노래 불러달라고? - 아뇨!
Here, it goes something like this--
이렇게 하면 돼
l was wondering if you could come watch me ride tomorrow.
내일 응원 와줘요
Yeah, yeah. We'll both ride, man.
그래, 알았어 같이 파도 타는 거야
-No, not just-- In the contest. -Contest? What contest?
- 시합장에요 - 무슨 시합?
The Big Z Memorial. Remember that one?
'빅 2 추모배' 서핑 대회요
I know I'm asking a lot...
무리한 부탁이지만
..but it would really, really be...
아저씨가 와준다면
.. the biggest thing in the world to me if you could come.
저한텐 정말로 큰 영광이에요
-You still want to be a part of that? -Absolutely.
- 시합에 나가고 싶어? - 당연하죠?
-Why do you want me there anyway? -l thought you'd want to be there.
- 나는 왜? - 제 시합 보시라고요
-l don't know why it's a big deal. -It's no big deal.
- 안 될 것도 없잖아요 - 별거 아냐
Why won't you come?
근데 왜요?
-I'm not coming. -Why?
- 난 안 간다 - 왜요?
-Give it a rest. -It's getting cold, guys.
- 그만하자 - 음식 다 식겠네
-Tell me why you're hiding. -Hiding?
- 왜 숨어살죠? - 뭐?
-Why are you hiding? -I'll have to eat all this by myself.
- 이유가 뭐예요? - 혼자 먹어야겠네
Why didn't you come back after you fell off the wave?
파도에 휠쓸리곤 왜 사라졌죠?
That wave.
그 파도는…
That last day, winning had become everything to me.
을 은 우증42 징측랐
1 knew I was gonna beat Tank.
승완0 0글 줄 을요0
But then, you know, he starts to surf circles around me.
지온 용크는 중순 .가줄흘을 선오요04
! saw what he was doing. ! couldn't do what he was doing.
은 응오 옷 을 ㅡ72 .24줄흠흠
Times had changed.
47402 세
! didn't want to walk back on that beach with all my fans there.
8204 를 7을 관을 은
A loser. Everyone looking at Big Z, the loser, the has-been.
4040.07 오즘으로 졸42422 삶요<
So...
2204…
Big Z's dead, and that's how it's gonna stay.
빅 2는 그렇게 죽은 거야
Let me play you that song.
노래 불러줄게
What about "never give up"? What about "find a way"?
포기하지 말고 길을 찾으라더니
-You're giving up. You're giving up! -Yeah, I'm giving up. That's my way.
- 아저씬 포기했어요 - 그래, 난 포기했어, 그게 내 길이니까
-Giving up. -l thought you were the one guy.
- 포기했어 - 아져 존경했어요
You don't like it, find your own way.
이제 제 길을 찾아가
Leave me out of it.
난 빠질래
I messed up. I'm just--
실수 했어요
I'm...not good.
난 형편없거든요
This is when I needed someone. I needed him.
그가 정말 필요했어요
It's hard enough losing one dad, but....
잃어내린 아터질 찾았다고…
-What do you mean by--? -Nothing.
- 무슨 풋0죠2 - 아네요
Nothing, man. Forget it.
아무것도 아네요
Peaceful. Peaceful. I'm in peace. I come in peace.
난 적이 아네요 평화를 원해요
-Cody! -Joe!
- 코디! - 조!
-I've been looking everywhere for you! -You've been looking for me?
- 얼마나 찾았다고! - 날 찾았어요?
I didn't lose you on the whale. I'm not gonna lose you now.
내가 데려왔는데 책임을 져줘야지
-Thank you. Seriously, thank you. -Radical.
- 고마워요 - 멋져
They're starting! Cody, we gotta go! Come on!
대회가 시작됐어 빨리 가자
Wait a minute. Joe?
잠깐만요, 조?
I'm sorry. Watch this, dude. Il can speak their language.
미안해, 잘 봐 난 원주민 말 배웠어
I totally need my board. I don't know where it is. gotta go find it.
난 보드 찾아올게
-I'll see you in the lineup. -See you, Joe.
- 경기할 때 보자 - 이따 봐요
The tenth annual Big Z is about to get underway...
4 70 '옥 2 추오44" 240호
..and, whoa, it is the day of days.
그 악0 을리<747
Big mountainous bombs marching into our coastline.
정전 한 도올 글 2422는군요
Kelly Slater, on a danger level, one to ten, give me a number.
704 70244 유흥지수을 4422
Twenty.
20!
-Wow. Rob? -There'll be blood.
- 좀2 - 피바다 되겠어요
I'm scared, and I'm in the booth!
중#4 수 @은 자오 플2슨군요7
-What are you doing here? -Mike.
- 여기서 뭐해? - 마이크
You're gonna kill yourself. Don't do this to yourself.
이건 자살행위야 출전 포기해
Look what happened last time.
지난번 일 잊었어?
-It's good to see you back. -Are you serious?
- 잘 돌아왔다 - 진짜요?
You're gonna be a real crowd pleaser.
관중들이 기뻐하겠군
I'm telling you, these people are gonna eat you up.
너의 컴백을 열렬히 환영할거야
-I'll be expecting big things from you. -Thank you.
- 너한테 기대가 커 - 고마워요
People, big announcement. Cody Maverick, he's back.
폴04.7.4으 을 고47 4420
The Wipeout King is back...
졸4요증<474
..and I'm gonna tell you, start looking for the sharks.
27772 의으
They'll be circling because there's gonna be blood.
0 474 을를 54 살육9 2을
Spectacular carnage today.
공것 증24요
Thank you! Reggie Belafonte. Little guy, big hair, big thoughts, big heart.
작아도 가슴은 넓은 레지 벨라폰테였습니다
Look at this. You're going down, snowflake.
이게 누구야? 년 오늘 끝장이야
I'm gonna make you wish you were never even hatched.
알 깨고 나온 걸 후회하게 해주마
You want to see my trophies?
트로피 보여줄까?
Arnold, no.
아놀드, 안 돼
About 24 surfers battling their way out to the--
24용9 산수흘 줄로 위증 4747
Good golly! Make that 18.
02 을조.7 76응으로 출었군요
Rob, after such a heavy wipeout earlier in the week...
지은센 용신으와온 고47 손수424
...what do you think is going through Maverick's mind?
조여음 하4@82
He's gonna have to stay focused and channel that energy into good places.
종중륙을 우고 조전을 24404요
When are you gonna get a life?
언제 펜 될래?
You are a nobody.
년 아무것도 아냐
You should've stayed in Antarctica, kid.
남극을 떠난 게 실수였어
He made it! Yeah, good.
아직도 멀쩌? 다행이네
What an amazing first ride mind-blower from Maverick.
고7 산주, 7화전 우440 총2427477
Did you guys see that?
봤어요?
Man. I thought I was gonna lose it, and then I just...
중심을 잃을 뻔 했는데
I just let go, you know. I let go, and there it was.
마음을 비웠더니 더 잘되더라고요
Wow, it's been an amazing day...
20 오우 꼴안 42
...0f shredding in less than stellar conditions...
4 고한 선수즐0
..but 1 never would have guessed our three finalists.
글증4 홀읍47<
Well, Sal, it's no surprise that Tank Evans...
탱크가 결승에 오른 건
..has just breezed his way into the finals.
놀랄 일이 아니죠
And Cody Maverick, from a horrible wipeout a few days ago to this.
지완 코7요 02472 지2 조그
And Chicken Joe from Sheboygan. Who would have guessed it?
글증4 오른 곳은 4 272820죠
! have never seen a finals like this.
02 글증존은 산성 저증004요
-We're in the finals, Joe. -No way! We get to surf some more?
- 결승에 진출했어! - 서핑 더하는 거야?
Isn't it exciting? Look at that. This is great, huh?
정말 신나지 않아? 저걸 보라고
You know, you should know this. The Tank loves you.
미리 말해두지만 탱크는 너휠 사랑해
Looks like this will be the easiest year ever.
올해 우승은 아주 첩겠어
No way. Cody, did you hear that? It's gonna be easy.
들었어? 아주 쉬울 거래
Are you loving this?
모두 즐거우십니까?
So who would you like to see win the trophy?
누.2 우증환으연 좋겼472
It's not so important to me.
그건 안 중요해요
Friends are better than anything in the world.
이 세상에 친구보다 소중한 건 없거든요
Friends are forever.
친구는 영원하지만
Trophies, you never know what they can have happen to them.
트로피는 잠깐이죠
-That was awesome, mate. -Muy impresivo, my friend.
- 정말 끝내줬어 - 멋졌어, 친구
Thank you, bro. Thanks.
다들 고마워
-Finals. -Hey!
결승이라니!
Yeah. I know. I can't even--
알아, 내가 결승에…
I think I can win this thing. It's too much right now.
우승할 수 있어 느낌이 팍팍 와
-Well, that's all you came for. -What?
- 그래서 왔잖아 - 뭐?
-What is that supposed to mean? -You made it pretty clear last night...
- 무슨 뜻이야? - 어젯밤에 그랬잖아
.. that winning's more important to you than Z or me.
친구들보단 우승이 중요하다고
But, hey, maybe you'll get to take your stupid trophy home.
우승 트로피 안고 멋지게 돌아가
-Lani. Come on. -Come here, you!
- 잠깐만 - 이리 와
How about this, huh?
포즈 좀 취해
Let me tell you something. You win this thing, we're going places!
이번에 우승하면 나랑 계약하자고
Look at this kid. He is a champ!
오늘 새 챔피언이 탄생할 겁니다
Tank, nine-time defending champion. He will roll on you.
9회 연승의 탱크가 강력한 우승 후보예요
Expect him to win this thing. It's basically a contest for second place.
지을환 2유 4충0 을 2477
First, I'm gonna take you down. Then I'm gonna fry the chicken.
널 무참히 깨버리고 기름에 튀길 거야
That cloud looks just like a kitten.
구름 모양이 고양이랑 똑같아
Maverick and Evans take off.
졸을아는 용그요 고7
Mine!
내 파도야!
And it's Evans dropping in.
22 27오 20즌 용크
And Tank's playing games, blocking Maverick's every move.
고유 으음 .그로으증<7<
Maverick sticks a rail.
2200 260즌 고
Tank Evans down! ! have never, ever seen this before!
성07는 용그7 02 긍우든 2증 홍477
But I'd love to see it again.
04 한 # 오고 송군요
Cody trying to take back the wave that Tank snaked from him.
옹그4 @은 4오을 #옷으2쓴 고7
Evans toying with him, not paying attention.
종은지는 웅크
And there's the outside rail. Evans goes down.
중@을 으 #024777
And it's Maverick with this new-school move. We'll call it "The Maverick."
고으 4오운 가출 0흥204 '0르7
And look at this. Maverick scoring big.
고은오 줄로 근 경수를 판<74
Oh, it's so cute. It's got little paws and the whiskers.
어 그렇게 귀엽니 앙증맞은 발하며, 멋진 수염
Chicken Joe with a no-paddle drop-in!
준7흘 승도 와 오으4 훌22 22
-Here we go! -Nobody needs to help this chicken.
- 간다! - 정을 44은한 율유<77
I'm flying!
날아간다!
Maverick and Joe tied, and no score for Tank Evans? Unbelievable.
코디와 치킨은 동점 탱크는 무득점입니다
Surfers, this is your final wave!
선수흘 지으 20887
-Joe, this is it. This wave wins it. -Yeah, man!
- 이번만 잘하면 우승이야! - 신난다!
This wave is stacking up to be a beautiful tube.
420한 2오증군0 안을0겼군요
Maverick should score big on this one!
고47 산수 골호유 찬스
But wait! Evans drops in.
앵그유 으공7
It looks like Evans is gonna take out the chicken.
지고00 20404 을를 곳 글군요
What's Maverick doing?
고472 와 242죠2
-Go, Joe, go! -Got it! Let's go!
- 조, 빨리 가! - 알았어!
! don't believe this. This contest was Maverick's to win.
유증할 화음 슬22즌 고477
Now Evans pushing Maverick out of bounds and into The Boneyards.
코디를 해골밭으로 몰고 가는 탱크!
-Tank, look out! -You look out!
- 탱크, 조심해요! - 너나 조심해!
Code!
코디!
-Cody, come on. -Z!}
잡아!
Paddle! Come on! Dig! Faster! Come on. Dig!
이쪽으로 헤엄쳐! 더 빨리!
Don't dig! Don't dig!
가만있어!
What?
네?
Let the wave carry you!
파도에 밀려와야 돼
You're gonna have to time it!
타이밍 잘 맞춰
You're gonna come right here, right to me!
파도에 떠밀려서 나한테 오는 거야
Five...four....
다섯, 넷
Three...two...one.
셋, 둘, 하나
Where's Cody?
코디 어디 있어?
Don't touch it! Don't touch that!
손대지 마!
This is a reminder of the young surfer...
스포츠를 위해 목숨을 바친
..who gave his life for the sport he loved.
젊은 서퍼의 귀중한 유품이야
There you are.
무사했구나!
I can't believe it! 1 can't believe it.
믿기질 않아요 안 믿긴다고요
You came back.
와줬군요
You saved my life, man. Thank you.
날 구해줬어요 고마워요
Hey, hey, come on. You're gonna tip us!
그만해, 잘못하면 보드 뒤집혀
Well, I lost.
우승을 놓쳤어요
Me too.
나도 그랬다
Come on. Let's go, loser.
가자고, 패배자
You want to help me out here?
좀 도와줄래?
You know the routine. Come on. Long. That's it. Smooth, you know. Come on.
어떻게 하는지 알잖아 길고 부드럽게
Young Joey MacEnroe was a beacon for a new generation.
'조이 맥켄로'는 젊은 세대에게 귀감이 됐어요
May he rest in peace.
편히 잠들기를…
So, what am I bid for the board? Who'll give me 30? 30, come on.
보드 경매할게요 30달러 없어요?
-Don't touch his stuff, man. -Pal, if you want to bid--
- 보드에서 손 떼 - 갖고 싶으면…
-Give me that. -Hey--!
이리 내뇌
Hey. Hey, everyone.
안녕하세요
-How you been? -Oh, my gosh!
- 잘 지냈어요? - 맘소사!
-Yeah... -Hey, man, that's Z.
그래요
..that's me.
나예요
Skank, what's happening, man?
탱크, 잘 지냈나?
Got a little sand in your egg sac there, fella.
알집에 모래 들어갔어
-Where have you been, Z? -What happened?
- 어디 갔었어요? - 어떻게 된 거죠?
Oh, you know...
뭐랄까
..1 got lost for a little while. But that kid there, Cody...
길을 잃고 좀 헤묘 하지만 코디가
.. he pointed the way back.
돌아오는 길을 알려줬어요
Could you please shut that off? Could you give me a minute?
카메라 좀 끌래요? 창피하단 말이에요
Check it out! How about this?
정말 굉장하죠?
You want to talk about talent scout? People find talent.
매니저의 능력 정말 대단하죠?
I bring them back from the dead. The now living legend, ladies and--
죽은 펜도 살려냈잖아요
-Shut up. -What? Shut up?
- 좀 닥쳐! - 뭐라고요?
I'm not a legend. I'm a guy looking for some nice waves, some good friends.
난 전설이 아냐, 친구와 서핑을 사랑하는 팽권이지
Hey, guys, the swell is happening over on the north shore!
북쪽 해안 파도가 끝내주는데 갑시다
I'm right behind you, Z.
금방 갈게요
Come back here! You don't just walk away! Come on!
돌아와! 나랑 계약하자고!
He's taking this loss pretty hard.
상심이 큰 것 같군요
Tank, how does it feel to lose after nine time--
10회 연속 우승을 놓친 심정이?
l wasn't kissing her. You can't have her!
키스한 거 아네요 내 여자야!
Can we get a few words?
- 인터뷰 좀? - 네
You gave up the trophy to help Joe. What's that about?
조를 위해서 우승을 포기한 이유가?
You know, Rob, that's what friends do.
친구보다 소중한 건 세상에 없으니까요
-How's it feel to win, Joe? -l won?
- 우승 소감이, 조? - 내가 이겼어요?
Come on! I'll tell my mom. Gimme. Gimme!
엄마한테 이를 거야! 트로피 내뇌!
Oh, Lia! Oh, Lia.
내 사랑 리아!
Don't you walk away from me! lam Reggie Belafon--
냉큼 돌아오지 못해! 난 레지라고!
Turn that thing off. Mikey! You are so fired!
당장 카메라 꺼요! 마이키, 년 해고야!
I can't imagine a better day.
듣던 중 반가운 소리네요!
Dude, this-- This whole experience has just been--
평생 잊지 못할 경험을 했어요
It's amazing. Z?
정말 대단해요 2요?
I don't think I've ever had a better friend to me in my life.
세상에서 가장 좋은 친구를 얻었죠
It's just really cool to have everything I need.
2 오슨 글 2220요
-Don't do it. Help! -Arnold!
살려줘!
To be honest, man, I'm kind of, like, bored of talking about myself.
제 얘기만 하니까 슬슬 지겹네요
So, is that cool? You guys got what you need?
가 봐도 되요? 많이 찍었죠?
-We got it -All right. Be good!
- - 그럼!
Cowabunga!
카우병가!
Of course we're proud of him!
당연히 자랑스럽죠
What mother wouldn't be proud of him?
엄마 맘은 다 똑같아요
We're so full of proudness.
뿌듯해 죽겠네요
You know what? He followed his dream...
꿈을 이고
..and he went out there, and now he's coming home with the trophy.
우승 트로피를 들고 돌아온다잖아요
l can't wait to see his trophy.
빨리 보고 싶어요
There's not really a trophy.
스로2슨 와요
Is there, like, a big shell or something like that?
그럼 커다란 조개겁질이라도?
There's no shell. There's no trophy. Well, he didn't win.
조.개졸도 와요 유증을 옷황.4은요
What?
네?
How bad was it? Did he get smoked?
그럼 었어요? 개 박살 났죠?
-He was in the finals. -Second place? That's losing.
- 결승엔 진출했잖아 - 2등이면 진 거예요
-Winning is not everything, Glen. -Right.
- 우승이 전부는 아냐 - 전부예요
Look at what Cody did--
코디는…
Go back to the "winning isn't everything" thing.
우승이 전부가 아니라고요?
That doesn't compute, really.
말이 안 되잖아요
You know what, Glen? I really hope someday you can be more like Cody.
네가 코디 반만 따라가도 엄마는 소원이 없겠다
This interview is over.
인터뷰 끝내요
Remember when were talking about you leaving? That was great.
언제 떠날 건지 물어본 거 기억나죠?
Remember when you were gonna go?
대체 언제 가요?
-We were gonna go-- -You should still go.
- 꾼20 .2혹은… - 빨리 가세요
It's technical equipment.
474 고 요7
I know what I'm doing. I can unplug one of your little Hollywood devices.
내가 바보인줄 알아요? 나도 전원 글 줄 안다고요
The lighting thing, whatever you call that...
조명이 뭔지도 알고
..and then the microphone thing.
마이크도 알아요
Go back to Hollywood.
할리우드로 가내려요
Cody would never do this.
코디한테 좀 배우라고